<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type = "text/xsl" href = "serious-video-games.xsl"?>

<!DOCTYPE catalogue SYSTEM "serious-video-games.dtd">

<catalogue>
  <genres>
    <genre id="gr-0001" title="Games for Health" >
      <image source="health_title"/>
      <description>
        Games for Health are games that aim to either promote 
        health or to prevent, diagnose or treat (chronic) diseases. 
        These games, which are generally considered serious games, 
        aim to influence health outcomes by increasing the user's 
        knowledge and changing their behaviors through play.
      </description>
    </genre>
    <genre id="gr-0002" title="Advergames">
      <image source="advergames_title"/>
      <description>
        An advergame is a form of advertising in video games, 
        in which the video game is developed by or in close 
        collaboration with a corporate entity for purposes of 
        advertising a brand-name product. While other video games 
        may use in-game advertising (such as an advertisement 
        on a virtual billboard or branding on an in-game object), 
        an advergame is differentiated by the Interactive 
        Advertising Bureau as a "game specifically designed 
        around product or service being advertised". 
      </description>
    </genre>
    <genre id="gr-0003" title="Games for Training">
      <image source="training_title"/>
      <description>
        Games for training, also known as serious 
        games or edutainment games, are video games 
        that are designed to educate or train players 
        in a specific subject or skill. These games are 
        often used in education, corporate training, and 
        military training, and can be used to teach a wide 
        variety of topics, such as leadership, teamwork, 
        problem-solving, and technical skills. Games for 
        training can be effective at engaging and motivating 
        learners, and can be used to supplement traditional 
        teaching methods or to create immersive, interactive 
        learning experiences.
      </description>
    </genre>
    <genre id="gr-0004" title="Games for Education">
      <image source="education_title"/>
      <description>
        Educational games are games explicitly designed with 
        educational purposes, or which have incidental or 
        secondary educational value. All types of games may 
        be used in an educational environment, however 
        educational games are games that are designed to 
        help people learn about certain subjects, expand 
        concepts, reinforce development, understand a historical 
        event or culture, or assist them in learning a skill 
        as they play. Game types include board, card, and 
        video games.
      </description>
    </genre>
    <genre id="gr-0005" title="Games for Science and Research">
      <image source="science_title"/>
      <description>
        Games for science and research often have a specific scientific or research-related goal,
        such as mapping the brain, collecting data on spatial navigation,
        or identifying patterns in DNA sequences. Games for science and 
        research can be used to engage the general public in scientific 
        research, to collect data that would be difficult or impossible 
        to gather through traditional means, or to help researchers understand 
        complex systems or solve problems. These games can be an effective way 
        to promote scientific literacy and encourage people to learn about and 
        contribute to scientific research.
      </description>
    </genre>
    <genre id="gr-0006" title="Production">
      <image source="production_title"/>
      <description>
        Games for production, also known as factory simulation games
        or tycoon games, are video games that simulate the management
        and operation of a production facility. These games often involve
        tasks such as gathering resources, building structures and machines,
        and automating production processes in order to create a product or 
        service. Games for production can be used to teach players about
        various aspects of production, such as supply chain management,
        resource allocation, and quality control. These games can also
        be used to challenge players to find the most efficient and
        effective ways to produce goods or services.
      </description>
    </genre>
    <genre id="gr-0007" title="Games as Work">
      <image source="work_title"/>
      <description>
        Games for work, also known as gamification or gamified training,
        are video games or game-like elements that are used to engage 
        and motivate employees in their work. These games can be used 
        to teach new skills, encourage teamwork and collaboration, 
        or improve productivity. Games for work can be incorporated 
        into training programs, used as part of a rewards or recognition system, 
        or implemented as part of a company's culture and values. Gamification 
        can be an effective way to engage and motivate employees, and can be 
        used in a variety of industries and settings.
      </description>
    </genre>
  </genres>
  <sectors>
    <sector id="sr-0001" title="Government &amp; NGO">
      <image source="government_sector"/>
      <description>
        A government and NGO serious game is a type of simulation game that is used by government 
        agencies and non-governmental organizations (NGOs) to train employees, educate the public, and solve problems. 

        These games can be used to train employees in a variety of skills, such as leadership, 
        teamwork, and problem-solving. They can also be used to educate the public about a particular issue, or to 
        explore different approaches to solving problems.

        Government and NGO serious games can be played on a computer, or they can be played in a physical setting. 

        Overall, government and NGO serious games are an important tool for these organizations to train and prepare 
        employees, and to educate the public and explore new approaches to solving problems.
      </description>
    </sector>
    <sector id="sr-0002" title="Defense">
      <image source="defense_sector"/>
      <description>
        A defense serious game is a type of simulation game that is used by military and 
        defense organizations to train personnel, plan strategies, and test new equipment.

        These games can be used to train personnel in a variety of skills, including 
        combat tactics, leadership, and decision-making. They can also be used to test new 
        equipment or to explore different strategies and scenarios.

        Defense serious games can be played on a computer, or they can be played in a physical
        setting with simulated equipment. 

        Overall, defense serious games are an important tool for military and defense organizations
        to train and prepare personnel for a wide range of real-world situations.
      </description>
    </sector>
    <sector id="sr-0003" title="Healthcare">
      <image source="healtchcare_sector"/>
      <description>
        A healthcare serious game is a type of simulation game that is used in the healthcare 
        industry to train professionals, educate the public, and explore different treatment options.
        
        These games can be used to train professionals in a variety of skills,
        including patient care, diagnosis, and treatment. They can also be used to educate
        the public about health issues or to explore different treatment options.

        Healthcare serious games can be played on a computer, or they can be played
        in a physical setting with simulated equipment. 

        Overall, healthcare serious games are an important tool for the healthcare industry to train and prepare 
        professionals and to explore new treatment options.
      </description>
    </sector>
    <sector id="sr-0004" title="Marketing &amp; Communications">
      <image source="marketing_sector"/>
      <description>
        A marketing and communications serious game is a type of simulation 
        game that is used by organizations to train employees in marketing
        and communications skills, and to explore different marketing and 
        communication strategies. 

        Marketing and communications serious games can be used to train employees 
        in a variety of skills, including sales, advertising, and public relations. 
        They can also be used to explore different marketing and communication strategies, 
        and to test the effectiveness of different messages and campaigns.

        Marketing and communications serious games can be played on a computer, 
        or they can be played in a physical setting. 

        Overall, marketing and communications serious games are an important tool for organizations to 
        train and prepare employees in marketing and communication skills, and to explore new strategies.
      </description>
    </sector>
    <sector id="sr-0005" title="Education">
      <image source="education_sector"/>
      <description>
        An education serious game is a type of game that is designed to teach players about
        a particular subject or issue in an interactive and engaging way. These games 
        are often used in formal education settings, such as schools and universities, 
        as well as in other settings, such as museums and science centers.

        Education serious games can cover a wide range of subjects, from math and science 
        to history and the arts. They can be played on a computer, or they can be played 
        in a physical setting. Many education serious games are designed to be played in groups, 
        which can encourage collaboration and teamwork.

        Education serious games can be an effective way to engage learners and to make learning
        more interactive and enjoyable. They can also be used to supplement traditional teaching 
        methods, or to provide additional support for learners who need extra help.

        Overall, education serious games are an important tool for teaching and learning, 
        and they can be used to support a variety of educational goals.
      </description>
    </sector>
    <sector id="sr-0006" title="Corporate">
      <image source="corporate_sector"/>
      <description>
        A corporate serious game is a type of simulation game that is used by businesses and organizations 
        to train employees, explore new ideas, and solve problems. 

        Corporate serious games can be used to train employees in a variety of skills, such as leadership, 
        teamwork, and problem-solving. They can also be used to explore new ideas and strategies, and to test the effectiveness 
        of different approaches.

        Corporate serious games can be played on a computer, or they can be played in a physical setting. 

        Overall, corporate serious games are an important tool for businesses and organizations to train and prepare employees, 
        and to explore new ideas and approaches.
      </description>
    </sector>
    <sector id="sr-0007" title="Industry">
      <image source="industry_sector"/>
      <description>
        An industry serious game is a type of simulation game that is used by a specific industry to train employees, 
        explore new ideas, and solve problems. 

        Industry serious games can be used to train employees in a variety of skills, such as leadership, 
        teamwork, and problem-solving. 

        Industry serious games can be played on a computer, or they can be played in a physical setting. 
        They can be used to train individuals or teams, and they can be customized to meet the specific needs of 
        different industries.

        Overall, industry serious games are an important tool for specific industries to train and prepare employees,
        and to explore new ideas and approaches.
      </description>
    </sector>
  </sectors>
  <games>
   <game title="Vital Signs: Emergency Department"
          id="gm-0001">
      <description>
        Play a doctor in Vital Signs: Emergency 
        Department and challenge your medical knowledge to help 
        treat a wide array of characters that come into the ER 
        that day. Unlike medical school everybody can enroll in 
        Vital Signs with nothing down and as little as a 
        commitment of 30 minutes or less!

        Come to a diagnosis by selecting from a wide range of tests 
        and prescribe medications or other treatments to give your 
        patients the best possible care. However, remain vigilant 
        and flexible! Your decisions and how you handle the influx 
        of patients that come in during your shift will decide 
        who gets to go home and who ends up in the morgue!
      </description>
      <about genres="gr-0001" 
              sectors="sr-0003"
              logo="vs_ed_logo" 
              website="https://www.vitalsignsgames.com/" 
              releaseDate="October 15, 2020" 
              contentRating="mature_17_plus">
          <supportedLanguages>English</supportedLanguages> 
      </about>
      <requirements>
        <minimum>
          <os>Windows 7 64-bit</os>
          <processor> Intel Core 2 Duo 2.4GHz</processor>
          <memory>2 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>NVIDIA GeForce GTX 960</graphics>
          <storage>2 GB available space</storage>
        </minimum>
        <recommended>
          <os>Windows 10 64-bit</os>
          <processor>AMD Ryzen 3 | Intel i5 Skylake</processor>
          <memory>4 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>NVIDIA GeForce GTX 960 or better</graphics>
          <storage>2 GB available space</storage>
        </recommended>
      </requirements>
      <gallery>
        <image source="vital_signs_1"/>
        <image source="vital_signs_3"/>
        <image source="vital_signs_2"/>
        <image source="vital_signs_4"/>
      </gallery>
    </game>
    <game title="FIFA 23"
          id="gm-0002">
      <description>Experience the thrill of the world's most popular 
      sport with "Fifa 23." Play as your favorite national team or 
      club and compete in leagues, tournaments, and exhibitions. 
      With improved gameplay mechanics and realistic player models, 
      "Fifa 23" brings the excitement of football to life.</description>
      <about genres="gr-0002" 
              sectors="sr-0004"
              logo="FIFA_23_logo" 
              website="https://www.ea.com/games/fifa/fifa-23" 
              releaseDate="September 26, 2022" 
              contentRating="everyone">
          <supportedLanguages>English, French, Spanish, German, Italian, Dutch, Portuguese, Russian, Polish, Czech, Japan</supportedLanguages> 
        </about>
      <requirements>
        <minimum>
          <os>Windows 7 or higher</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i3-2100 or AMD Phenom II X4 965</processor>
          <memory>8 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>Nvidia GeForce GTX 460 or AMD Radeon R7 260</graphics>
          <storage>50 GB available space</storage>
        </minimum>
        <recommended>
          <os>Windows 10</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i5-3550 or AMD FX-8150</processor>
          <memory>8 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>Nvidia GeForce GTX 670 or AMD Radeon R9 270</graphics>
          <storage>50 GB available space</storage>
        </recommended>
      </requirements>
      <gallery>
        <image source="fifa1"/>
        <image source="fifa2"/>
        <image source="fifa3"/>
        <image source="fifa4"/>
      </gallery>
    </game>
    <game title="Minecraft"
          id="gm-0003">
      <description>"Minecraft" is a sandbox video game that allows players to build and explore 
      virtual worlds made up of blocks. It was developed by Markus Persson and released by Mojang in 2011.
      In "Minecraft," players can explore a vast procedurally-generated world made up of a variety
      of different biomes, including forests, mountains, caves, and oceans. They can gather resources,
      craft items, and build structures using a variety of different blocks.
      "Minecraft" has become a hugely popular game, with millions of players all over the world. 
      It has also been used in education settings as a tool for teaching creativity, engineering, 
      and computer programming.</description>
      <about genres="gr-0003" 
              sectors="sr-0005"
              logo="minecraft_logo" 
              website="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us" 
              releaseDate="November 18, 2011" 
              contentRating="everyone_10_plus">
          <supportedLanguages>English, French, Spanish, German, Czech, Japan, Portuguese, Russian, Korean, Turkish</supportedLanguages>
        </about>
      <requirements>
        <minimum>
          <os>Windows 7 or later, macOS, or Linux</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i3-3210 3.2 GHz / AMD A8-7600 APU 3.1 GHz or equivalent</processor>
          <memory>4 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>Intel HD Graphics 4000 (Ivy Bridge) or AMD Radeon R5 series (Kaveri line) with OpenGL 4.4*</graphics>
          <storage>At least 1GB of free space</storage>
        </minimum>
        <recommended>
          <os>Windows 10</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i5-4690 3.5GHz / AMD A10-7800 APU 3.5 GHz or equivalent</processor>
          <memory>8 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics> NVIDIA GeForce 700 Series or AMD Radeon Rx 200 Series (excluding integrated chipsets) with OpenGL 4.5</graphics>
          <storage>4GB (SSD is recommended)</storage>
        </recommended>
      </requirements>
      <gallery>
        <image source="minecraft1"/>
        <image source="minecraft2"/>
        <image source="minecraft3"/>
        <image source="minecraft4"/>
      </gallery>
    </game>
    <game title="Sid Meier’s Civilization® VI"
          id="gm-0004">
      <description>Civilization VI is a turn-based 
      strategy game that allows players to build and 
      lead their own civilizations from the ground up. 
      Players can choose from a variety of historical 
      and fictional leaders and empires, and must make 
      decisions that will shape the course of their 
      civilization's history. The game features a range 
      of challenging scenarios, including natural disasters, 
      diplomatic relations, and military conflicts.</description>
      <about genres="gr-0004" 
              sectors="sr-0001"
              logo="civilization_VI_logo" 
              website="https://civilization.com/" 
              releaseDate="October 21, 2016" 
              contentRating="teen">
          <supportedLanguages>English, French, Spanish, German, Russian, Korean, Czech, Japan</supportedLanguages> 
        </about>
      <requirements>
        <minimum>
           <os>Windows 7 64bit / 8.1 64bit / 10 64bit</os>
            <processor>Intel Core i3 2.5 Ghz or AMD Phenom II 2.6 Ghz or greater</processor>
            <memory>4 GB RAM</memory>
            <graphics>1 GB NVIDIA GeForce 660 or AMD Radeon 7870 or equivalent DX11 GPU</graphics>
            <storage>12 GB available space</storage>
          </minimum>
          <recommended>
            <os>Windows 7 64bit / 8.1 64bit / 10 64bit</os>
            <processor>Fourth generation Intel Core i5 2.5 Ghz or AMD FX8350 4.0 Ghz or greater</processor>
            <memory>8 GB RAM</memory>
            <graphics>2 GB NVIDIA GeForce GTX 970 or AMD Radeon R9 290X or equivalent DX11 GPU</graphics>
            <storage>12 GB available space</storage>
        </recommended>
      </requirements>
      <gallery>
        <image source="civilization_VI_1"/>
        <image source="civilization_VI_2"/>
        <image source="civilization_VI_3"/>
        <image source="civilization_VI_4"/>
      </gallery>
    </game>
    <game title="Call of Duty: Modern Warfare II"
          id="gm-0005">
      <description>Call of Duty is a first-person shooter game series that takes place in various 
      historical and fictional settings, including World War II, the Cold War, and modern-day conflicts. 
      Players control a character and engage in a variety of military-themed missions, such as 
      completing objectives, eliminating enemy forces, and surviving enemy attacks. The series is known 
      for its intense and immersive gameplay, as well as its realistic graphics and sound effects. 
      In addition to the single-player campaign, Call of Duty also features a variety of multiplayer modes, 
      allowing players to compete against each other online. The series has been extremely popular since its 
      inception, and new installments are released regularly.
      </description>
      <about genres="gr-0005" 
              sectors="sr-0002"
              logo="call_of_duty_logo" 
              website="https://www.callofduty.com/" 
              releaseDate="October 28, 2022" 
              contentRating="adults_only">
          <supportedLanguages>English, French, Russian, German, Italian, Spanish, Japan, Polish</supportedLanguages> 
        </about>
      <requirements>
        <minimum>
          <os>Windows 10 64 Bit</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i3-6100 / Core i5-2500K or AMD Ryzen 3 1200</processor>
          <memory>8 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>NVIDIA GeForce GTX 960 or AMD Radeon RX 470</graphics>
          <storage>125 GB available space</storage>
        </minimum>
        <recommended>
          <os>Windows 10 64 Bit (latest update) or Windows 11 64 Bit (latest update)</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i5-6600K / Core i7-4770 or AMD Ryzen 5 1400</processor>
          <memory>12 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1060 or AMD Radeon RX 580</graphics>
          <storage>125 GB available space</storage>
        </recommended>
      </requirements>
      <gallery>
        <image source="call_of_duty1"/>
        <image source="call_of_duty2"/>
        <image source="call_of_duty3"/>
        <image source="call_of_duty4"/>
      </gallery>
    </game>
    <game title="Take on Mars"
          id="gm-0006">
      <description>Take on Mars is a simulation game that 
      allows players to explore and colonize the planet Mars. 
      Players must manage resources, conduct scientific research, 
      and build and maintain their base on the Martian surface. 
      The game includes realistic physics and terrain modeling, 
      and allows players to experience the challenges and 
      opportunities of Mars exploration.</description>
      <about genres="gr-0006" 
              sectors="sr-0001"
              logo="take_on_mars_logo" 
              website="https://mars.takeonthegame.com/" 
              releaseDate="February 9, 2017" 
              contentRating="teen">
          <supportedLanguages>English, French, Russian, German, Czech</supportedLanguages> 
        </about>
      <requirements>
        <minimum>
          <os>Windows 7 or higher</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i3-2115C or equivalent</processor>
          <memory>4 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>Nvidia GeForce GT 430 or equivalent</graphics>
          <storage>4 GB available space</storage>
        </minimum>
        <recommended>
          <os>Windows 10</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i5-3470 or equivalent</processor>
          <memory>8 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>Nvidia GeForce GTX 970 or equivalent</graphics>
          <storage>4 GB available space</storage>
        </recommended>
      </requirements>
      <gallery>
        <image source="take_on_mars_1"/>
        <image source="take_on_mars_2"/>
        <image source="take_on_mars_3"/>
        <image source="take_on_mars_4"/>
      </gallery>
    </game>
    <game title="World of Warcraft"
          id="gm-0007">
      <description>
      World of Warcraft (WoW) is a massively multiplayer online role-playing game
      set in the Warcraft fantasy universe. In the game, players create their own character and choose
      from a variety of races and classes, each with their own unique abilities and characteristics. 
      Players can explore a vast world, complete quests, interact with other players, and engage in a 
      variety of activities such as crafting, gathering resources, and battling monsters.
      
      The game has a subscription-based model and has a large player base, with millions of active players 
      around the world. WoW has received numerous accolades and is considered one of the most successful 
      and influential MMORPGs of all time.
      </description>
      <about genres="gr-0007" 
              sectors="sr-0002"
              logo="wow_logo" 
              website="https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-gb/" 
              releaseDate="November 23, 2004" 
              contentRating="teen">
          <supportedLanguages>English, French, Russian, German, Spanish, Portuguese</supportedLanguages> 
        </about>
      <requirements>
        <minimum>
          <os>Windows 7 64-bit</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i5-760 or AMD FX-8100 or later</processor>
          <memory>4 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>NVIDIA GeForce GTX 560 2GB or AMD Radeon HD 7850 2GB or Intel HD Graphics 530 (45W)</graphics>
          <storage>70 GB available space</storage>
        </minimum>
        <recommended>
          <os>Windows 10 64-bit</os>
          <processor>Intel Core i7-4770 or AMD FX-8310 or later</processor>
          <memory>8 GB RAM</memory>
          <graphics>NVIDIA GeForce GTX 960 or AMD Radeon R9 280 or later</graphics>
          <storage>70 GB available space</storage>
        </recommended>
      </requirements>
      <gallery>
        <image source="wow1"/>
        <image source="wow2"/>
        <image source="wow3"/>
        <image source="wow4"/>
      </gallery>
    </game>
  </games>
</catalogue>
